# 陕西·西安
Xi'an, Shaanxi
# 我们现在在一个小区里
We are in a community now
# 准备吃中午饭
Ready to eat lunch
# 路两边有很多小吃摊
There are many food stalls on both sides of the street
# 看看今天中午吃什么吧
Let’s see what to eat at this noon
# 早上起来还没有吃饱饭
I've been hungry for the entire morning
# 现在出来的时间是比较早吧
It’s still relatively too early for lunch
# 看了几家小店 都还没有打算开张
Some restaurants are still not open yet
# 走了半天 直到看到这锅肉
We've walked for a long time until we saw this pot of meat
# 我这两条腿真的是走不动路了
I’m really tired of walking
# 来的太早了 没想到这边的面条还没有做好
We came too early. Didn't expect that their noodles are not ready yet
# 不过门口的大锅已经支棱起来了
But their huge pot is ready
# 看里面的肉 真的是特别香
Look at the meat inside. It's very fragrant
# 一天这一锅肉够吗
Is one pot of meat enough for the whole day?
# 要不够下午再烧吧
We will make more in the afternoon if it needed
# 一会儿这个肉直接浇在面上吃的是吧
We pour the meat on the noodles later, right?
# 这个肉 一会儿烧好以后 每一碗都有 都含着有
After the meat is ready, we'll pour into every bowl.
# 在西安的面馆里 总少不了两种食材
There are always two ingredients in noodle restaurant in Xi'an
# 一种呢 是大蒜
One is garlic
# 另外一种是醋
The other is vinegar
# 怎么把它给忘了 还有辣子
How could I forget the last one, spicy pepper as well
# 我们今天吃的是卤面 面条是上锅蒸出来的
We are gonna have Lumian today. The noodles are steamed in a pot
# 面条出锅 然后在上面放上卤子
The noodles are steamed, and then gravy is pour on it
# 大碗的是13块钱 小碗的是11块钱
13 yuan for a large bowl, 11 yuan for a small bowl
# 每碗当中 都含有肉啊 菜啊
Meat and vegetable in every bowl
# 干的时间好长了
We’ve been working here for a long time
# 一个生意坚持这么久 太不容易了
You've been running the business for so long. That's not easy
# 那你没办法 你要生活的嘛
You have no choice. You gotta make a living
# 人要生活就是这样子
This is how it looks like to make a living
# 反正跟上班一样
It's like an employment
# 你上班 工作 有时候干也要干一辈子嘛 是吧
You got employed, go to work. That can also last a lifetime, right?
# 你人 你活着你不干 你咋么办
If you live without working, what can you do?
# 是不 你不干这个就得干那个
Correct? You need to work on something
# 都是些老顾客过来的是吧 附近上班的
Are those all old customers who work nearby?
# 老顾客多 干的时间长了 老顾客也多
Many old customers. We got many old customers after working here for a long time
# 但是新顾客也有
We also have new customers as well
# 反正可多顾客都说 （味道）还行
Anyway, many customers say that our Lumian is not bad
# 喜欢吃了他就爱吃
If they like it, they enjoy it
# 你有的人他不喜欢吃这种面 那咱能怎么办
What can you do if they don't like it
# 就是一碗面
Just a bowl of noodles
# 没有可香啊 像人家那种大口香得很
Not something super tasty as others restaurant
# 这没有 就很家常的味嘛
No. Just something very homestyle
# 就家常味
Homestyle flavor
# 我要一个大碗的 再加个蛋
I want a large bowl of Lumian and an egg
# 大碗的 加个蛋
Large bowl of Lumian with an egg
# 还是很多料的呀
Plenty of sides
# 辣子呢
How about spicy pepper
# 要
yeah
# 再来一勺？
One more spoon of spicy pepper?
# 可以 可以
sure
# 还有煎蛋
And fried egg?
# 好 谢谢
Yeah, thank you
# 不客气
You’re welcome
# 看我们的大碗卤面上来了
Our large bowl of Lumian is ready
# 不过我发现 后面的大哥在吃面之前会先剥蒜
I also found that the bro behind us peels the garlic before eating his noodles
# 13块钱的卤面 阿姨说够两个人吃的
Aunt said 13 yuan of Lumian is enough for two people to eat
# 确实不少
Sure it does
# 红的 黄的 绿的 各种各样的颜色应有尽有
Red, yellow and green, colorful
# 卤面里面除了有肉 菜花 豆角
There are meat, cauliflower, and beans in Lumian
# 此外呢 我们还加了一个蛋
We also added an egg
# 这个是什么
What’s this?
# 土豆
potato
# 阿姨刚才说 面条没有多好吃
Aunt said the noodles are not something super tasty
# 但是食材丰富 让人感觉食欲大开
But it has plenty of ingredients, which is so appetizing
# 面条是干的 没有任何的汤汁 加了辣子
The noodles are dry and without soup. But there is spicy pepper
# 这个焖面加上辣子 辣子是香而不辣的
Noodles with spicy pepper. The pepper is fragrant but not spicy
# 但是很下面条
Goes so well with noodles
# 觉得不够 这边还有
There’s more if you want more
# 这哪是用碗装 这是用盆装
This is not a bowl. It feels even like a pot
# 有能吃不饱的吗
Everyone will get full by this
# 谢谢
Thank you
# 面条稍微有些油 有些酱油的咸味
The noodles have a little bit of oil, and the salty taste from soy sauce
# 面和菜就是这么浑然一体
The noodles and sides are such a good combo
# 吃到现在 菜已经吃光了
Now all sides are gone
# 然后我们说 把辣子放进去
And as we said, we've mixed spicy pepper with the noodles
# 辣子都能当一道菜 配面条来吃
Even spicy pepper works as a side with the noodles
# 面馆里的面条是用这种蒸屉蒸出来的
Noodles in the restaurant are cooked in a steamer like this
# 每卖一屉才会再去蒸一屉
They make a new batch after the last batch is gone
# 不知不觉的工夫已经卖了三四屉了
About 3 or 4 steamers of noodles are gone in such a short time
# 叔 走了 拜拜
Uncle, we gotta go, bye
# 拍的差不多了 我们要走了
We've done filming, we gotta go
# 关 注
# 雪 鱼 探 店
Please subscribe